<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>imaging on Alexander Evitt</title>
    <link>https://alexanderevitt.github.io/tags/imaging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in imaging on Alexander Evitt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexanderevitt.github.io/tags/imaging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet Identification Project</title>
      <link>https://alexanderevitt.github.io/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexanderevitt.github.io/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>In collecting large amounts of images of the sky using the Transiting Exoplanet Survey Satellite (TESS), it was inevitable that some interesting objects would be observed. Most of these were eclipsing binary stars or Cepheid variable stars. In one case, however, I observed what I believe to be a comet, specifically C/2018 N2 (ASASSN), streaking through the frame of the camera. I was writing code that strung together full-frame images (FFIs) into videos and noticed that one of the sectors had an odd point of light streaking across the detector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sloan Digital Sky Survey Imaging</title>
      <link>https://alexanderevitt.github.io/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexanderevitt.github.io/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>This project is an offshoot of my main project, QuasVar, that produces beautiful astronomical images through the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Dataset. Admittedly, very little processing is needed, as SDSS handles most of its data beautifully. All I did was pull images of objects in different bands, align them, and combine them in RGB to make color images. SDSS has five bands, u, g, r, i, and z, which represent ultraviolet, red, green, infrared, and far-infrared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>